Shakil Ahmed

Software Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh shakil.hv@gmail.com +8801709776055

Professional summary

Full stack software engineer with 3+ years of professional expertise in the field fo web development with javascript and python. Have a strong hand over cloud and web technologies. I also have a solid understanding of database management, deployment, and testing. I am a team player with excellent communication and problem-solving skills, and am always eager to learn and grow in my field.

Experience

Software Engineer, Brainstation-23 Ltd

Jan 2021 - Present

- Built highly scalable data analytics SaaS platform for clients.
- Built chrome extension for google calendar.
- Wrote E2E test script with cypress.
- Developed CI/CD pipeline in multi-cloud environments.
- Documented and organized codebase.
- Facilitated all sprint cadences (planning, reviewing, retrospectives and standups) for engineering team.

Front-end Engineer, Hackverse

Sep 2018 - Dec 2020

- Worked with React.js to make web applications
- · Built PWA with react and next.js
- · Worked on SSR

Front-end Engineer, Codeboxr

Jan 2018 - Aug 2018

- · Worked with React.js to make web applications
- Built pixel perfect web templates

Projects

Testfuel

- Test case management and QA automation system
- Used React, Nest, MongoDB, TypeScript, Stripe

Shodai

- Grocery application
- Used React, Express, MongoDB, Docker

Boigram

- ML powered book recommedation system
- Used Next.js Django, PostgreSQL, Redis, Scikit-learn

Upstarter

- · Social site for startup community
- Used React, Apollo, GraphQL, Django, PostgreSQL

MeetingSpace

- SAAS for tracking and managing meeting in organization
- Used React, Redux, Material-UI, Express, NodeJS

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, React, D3, Redux-tookit, Next, Express, Nest, Node, MongoDB

Python, Django, PostgreSQL

Git, AWS, Docker, Figma

REST, GraphQL, Microservices, CI/CD

Communication, Leadership, Problem Solving

EDUCATION

BSc. in CSE

Daffodil International University 2017 - 2021

Certifications

- AWS Certified Solution Architect - Associate
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Profiles

GitHub • LinkedIn • Website